7esl.com 2019-05-18

# Privacy Policy - 7 E S L

This Privacy Statement is designed to provide information about 7esl.com (“7ESL”, “we”, “our” or “us”) privacy and data collection practices. This privacy policy does not apply to Sites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link or who may link to us. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third-party websites.

We have a few fundamental principles that we follow:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone.
  * The only personal information we store is your IP address in order to make the site function.

We use your Personal Information for three primary purposes:

  * To help you quickly find services or information on the site.
  * To help us create and deliver content most relevant to you.
  * To serve advertisement.
  * To act in urgent circumstances, protect the personal safety of users of the site, or the public.

##  **Personal identification information**

We may collect personally identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, subscribe to the newsletter, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address. We may store the IP addresses on our server. Users may visit our Site without sharing their name, email address, but the IP addresses are always collected and stored. We will collect personal identification information such as name, email address from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personal identification information except the IP address. If users refuse to supply personal identification information, it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities such as newsletter signup which requires a valid email address.

##  **Non-personal identification information**

We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information including IP address.

##  **Cookies**

Our Site may use “cookies” to enhance User experience. User’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web Site, and they may deploy cookies in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

##  **Advertising**

Ads appearing on our site may be delivered to Users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile non personal identification information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy policy does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

##  **How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps**

Some of the services are served by Google on 7ESL. Google uses its technology to serve ads to users based on their visit to our Site and other sites on the Internet. 7ESL uses the following Google services:

  * Google AdSense.
  * Google Analytics.

Your web browser automatically sends certain information to Google. This includes the URL of the page you’re visiting and your IP address.

[Please visit Google’s privacy policy page](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/) to learn more about how it uses information from sites or apps that use their services.

##  **Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Please visit their websites to learn more about how they collect your data.

##  **Sharing your personal information**

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes such as personalized ads, comments, newsletters, and others are outlined above.

We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission.

##  **Where we send your data**

As outlined above, 7ESL may send the required data to the following third-party networks:

  * Google and their partners – Please refer to [Google’s privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/).

##  **What rights you have over your data**

If you have left comments or signed up to newsletters, you can request to learn more about the personal data we hold about you, including data such as email address and name that you have provided to us. You can also request us to erase the data.

This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for analytics, administrative, legal, or security purposes.

##  **How we protect your information**

7ESL strictly protects the security of your personal information and honors your choices for its intended use. We carefully protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

  * We keep our software up to date and take a regular audit to improve security.
  * We use 2048 bit SSL certificate with modern TLS for the encryption.
  * We use the highly strong password and Two Factor Authentication everywhere.

##  **Changes to this privacy policy**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, 7ESL may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in 7ESL’s sole discretion.  We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

##  **Your acceptance of these terms**

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

##  **Who can I ask if I have any additional questions?**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement and our practices, or you have reason to believe 7ESL may have failed to adhere to this Privacy Statement, you can [**contact us**](https://7esl.com/contact/).
